<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Personal trading and development blog. Market analysis, trades and trader progress reports, educational resources, and trading-related content.</description>
    <link>https://koan-trading.com</link>
    <atom:link href="https://koan-trading.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>April Performance Review (2020)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/trader-progress/march-performance-review.jpeg" alt="April Performance Review - Tracked Using Edgewonk 2.0" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April has been an interesting month so far. Overall, we didn’t make much progress in terms of our PnL, but we did progress quite a bit in our overall read on the market, our setup optimization, and overall confidence. However, we didn’t make any progress at all on execution and psychology, succumbing to too many overleveraged, and oversized trades. This meant that we gave away most of our profits in the long-run, while risking our entire account. Not too happy with this, but it’s a work in progress!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Note: Currently, we are hedged into spot from 9188, along with a small short. This brings our unrealized monthly PnL% up to 10%, though our realized PnL% is only at 3.27%.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Trade Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my Edgewonk data for the month of April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/trader-progress/april-edgewonk-journal.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/trader-progress/april-edgewonk-journal.png&quot; alt=&quot;Edgewonk April Journal&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the cumulative data, automatically calculated by Edgewonk (numbers are in BTC):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Data&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Result&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Balance (Starting: 0.01)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.0856&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Trades Taken&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Winners&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Losers&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Winrate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;38%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Average Risk:Reward Ratio&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5.16&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Average R-Multiple&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.51&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Expectancy&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.00020359&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Data&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Result&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Trades Taken&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Winners&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Losers&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Winrate&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;48%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Average Risk:Reward Ratio&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4.3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Average R-Multiple&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.43&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Expectancy&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.00031479&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of the first half of April was spent doing trading related peripheral activities like building this website (Jekyll + Github Pages is awesome!), and getting my routine in order (developing meditation habits, exercise, diet, etc.). My first trade I took this month was actually on April 18th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m very happy with the improvements I’ve made in my market analysis. I feel that I have a more holistic approach to markets now, and have developed the proper habit of looking at the market from a complete perspective (ie. looking at funding, open interest, heatmaps in addition to the regular chart). Because of the recent choppy conditions, I have been testing a very low-time frame scalping strategy that relies on pockets of high volume on the footprint chart and exchange-specific price action to snipe entries for maximum risk:reward. I’m very happy to say that the testing has gone very well, and that I will continue to optimize this strategy before eventually fully adopting it into my setup list. I’m also very happy with the fact that I feel that I am able to read the footprint chart much better now, and am able to identify key areas of participation/interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, my pscyhology and discipline greatly lacked this month. Because of the strategy testing, this meant that I ended up stringing many losses together in a row as I was fine-tuning the strategy. This drawdown really ate at me, which caused me to end up over-leveraging and over-sizing on multiple positions without a stop. While it ended up working out this time, I need to be mindful that this was a fluke and should this behavior continue, I will be liquidated eventually one day. I attribute this lack of discipline to the fact that the account that I’m actively trading with is relatively small compared to my full balance, which makes me feel as if I don’t have any skin in the game. Will need to think of strategies to combat this behavior moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moving Forward&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to continue to improve my analysis skills, but my main focus is to work on my discipline. I will be spending some serious time developing a plan to address these issues (as recommended by Ray Dalio in his book Principles, of which you can find the chapter summaries on this blog!), as well as dedicating even more time to understanding the biases that I encounter while trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, meditation is now a habit in my life, so my next step is to re-incorporate exercise (been enjoying lots of at-home-boxing due to quarantine with the occasional dumbbell workout), yoga, and proper diet as I have been slacking on that end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, I hope your trading month has gone well! I’m very excited for things to come, and I hope you can join me on this journey. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://koan-trading.com//blog/trader-progress/2020/04/30/april-performance-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://koan-trading.com//blog/trader-progress/2020/04/30/april-performance-review/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thinking In Bets (Annie Duke) - Chapter 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/education/thinking-in-bets.jpeg" alt="Annie Duke - Thinking In Bets (Aidan Hornsby - Medium)" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 3 - Bet to Learn: Fielding the Unfolding Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapter 3 of Thinking In Bets is all about the way we look at outcomes and the biases that come with them. To improve, we need to be able to form a well-defined learning/feedback loop, be able to accurately analyze our outcomes through the spectrum of luck vs. skill (fielding outcomes), and understand our biases when it comes to our outcomes vs. the outcomes of our peers. Only by understanding these will we be able to effectively re-shape our habits of learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Experience can be an effective teacher. But, clearly, only some students listen to their teachers. The people who learn from experience improve, advanced, and (with a little bit of luck) become experts and leaders in their fields.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcomes are feedback&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Improvement goes beyond the accumulation of experience. Instead, it is what we do with our experiences that ultimately determines our progress. We need to be able to identify when the outcomes of our decisions contain useful lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;We can't just &quot;absorb&quot; experiences and expect to learn. As novelist and philosopher Aldous Huxley recognized, &quot;Experience is not what happens to a man; it is what a man does with what happens to him.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that in Chapter 2 we defined all our decisions as a type of bet. A bet on what we believe will create the most value and favorable future for us (though our bets don’t necessarily always work out). We can represent this type of bet like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Betting on a Future:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Belief –&amp;gt; Bet –&amp;gt; (Set of Outcomes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we want to do is to create a learning loop, whereby we are able to determine if our outcomes were largely determined by luck or a combination of our decisions. By doing this, we are then able to re-input this data into our belief formation and create a learning loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning Loop 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Belief –&amp;gt; Bet –&amp;gt; Outcome –&amp;gt; Bet 2 –&amp;gt; Belief –&amp;gt; …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Ideally, our beliefs and our bets improve with time as we learn from experience.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, games with incomplete information like poker and trading are rarely that simple. We are often left with too many unknowns to say for certain if our outcome was luck or decision-based. In order to achieve our long-term goals, we need to improve our ability to identify when outcomes have learn-able lessons and when they do not (learning to close the feedback loop). The first step is to recognize the existence of uncertainty (luck).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luck vs. skill: fielding outcomes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outcomes are influenced by two things, the influence of skill and the influence of luck. Unfortunately, it is often a combination of a variety of both skill and luck based variables (for example, club choice, setup, and swing are all influence of skill in the game of golf, but wind, unpredictable noises, the golfer’s genes, etc., are all influence of luck). By being able to identify which is which, we can update our learning loop:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning Loop 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Belief –&amp;gt; Bet –&amp;gt; Outcome –&amp;gt; Luck OR Skill? –&amp;gt; Belief –&amp;gt; …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;It is hard to get this right. Absent omniscience, it is difficult to tell why anything happened the way it did. The bet on whether to field outcomes into the luck or skill bucket is difficult to execute because of ambiguity.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working backward is hard: the SnackWell’s Phenomenon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are often multiple roads to the same outcome, making it difficult to work backwards from the quality of the outcome to determine the quality of our beliefs or decisions. But, learning about the way that uncertainty can hinder us and the patterns behind our errors and the motivations behind those errors can give us clues to figure out strategies that help us make better fielding decisions of our outcomes into luck or skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Outcomes don't tell us what is our fault and what isn't, what we should take credit for and what we shouldn't.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“If it weren’t for luck, I’d win every one”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our fielding errors aren’t random, and humans are predictably irrational. We love to take credit for the good stuff and blame the bad stuff on luck to avoid blame. This results in a poor learning process from our experiences, and is called “self-serving bias”. However, this bias can seriously harm our progress, as it means we will miss opportunities to examine our decisions to look for areas of improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Self-serving bias is a deeply embedded and robust thinking pattern. Understanding why this pattern emerges is the first step to developing practical strategies to improve our ability to learn from experience.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-or-nothing thinking rears its head again&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as it was important to stop thinking of our decisions in black-or-white but rather in gray (I am x% sure about my belief), we need to do the same with our outcome fielding (both self-serving bias and motivated reasoning stems from our need to create a self-positive narrative). This can be done in the same way as we discussed for motivated reasoning, where we think in shades of gray (this outcome was x% skill and x% luck).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Fielding outcomes with the goal of promoting our self-narrative and doing it in an all-or-nothing fashion alters our ability to make smart bets about why the future unfolded in a particular way.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People watching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching people is one of the most popular ways to learn or get experience. However, it has its biases too. The same way we use black-and-white thinking with our own outcomes, we do the same with our peers (but in an opposite fashion). When they have a good outcome, we think that they got lucky. If they have a bad outcome, we think that is because they don’t have enough skill. This has a negative effect on your progress a narrow-minded approach will cause you to miss many opportunities for learning and improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The systematic errors in the way we field the outcomes of our peers comes at a real cost. It doesn't just come at the cost of reaching our goals but also at the cost of compassion for others.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other people’s outcomes reflect on us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we are overconfident in our decision and quick to dismiss the skill of others is because we are naturally inclined for self-preservation and positive self-narrative. We all want to feel good about ourselves in the moment. In our minds, someone else winning automatically means that we are losing (humans are naturally competitive, and this concept of benchmarking and comparison is deeply rooted into our brains).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;A lot of the way we feel about ourselves comes from how we think we compare with others. This robust and pervasive habit of mind impedes learning... By shifting what it is that makes us feel good about ourselves, we can move to a more rational fielding of outcomes and a more compassionate view of others.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reshaping habit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One definable edge in highly successful people is their ability to field their outcomes. But, more importantly, the habits that they’ve built to be able to field those outcomes are different from the majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Habits operate in a neurological loop consisting of three parts: the cue, the routine, and the reward. A habit could involve eating cookies: the cue might be hunger, the routine going to the pantry and grabbing a cookie, and the reward a sugar high... Charles Duhigg, in The Power of Habit... the best way to deal with a habit is to respect the habit loop: &quot;To change a habit, you must keep the old cue, and deliver the old reward, but insert a new routine.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, a good outcome would cue the routine of crediting the result to our decision-making, creating a positive outlook for our self-narrative (vice versa for bad outcome). We want to change this by substituting what makes us feel good. Instead of feeling bad when we have to admit we’re wrong, what if we re-train the mind to feel bad because we might be missing a learning opportunity just to avoid blame? Or that we might be being too happy in our “good decision-making” instead of recognizing where we could have improved? Thinking like this will allow us to drive learning in a more objective and focused manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;We need a mindset shift. We need a plan to develop a more productive habit of mind... We can get to this mindset shift by behaving as if we have something at risk when we sort outcomes into the luck and skill buckets, because we do have a lot at risk on that fielding decision. Thinking in bets is a smart way to start building habits that achieve our long-term goals.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wanna bet? redux&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like we treat our decisions as a bet, we should treat our outcome fielding as a bet as well. This makes us examine and refine our beliefs, and to really think about whether or not something was more luck or skill. Thinking in bets allows us more open-minded exploration of alternative hypotheses, making it an effective tool to counteract self-serving bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In relation to the way we look at other people’s outcomes, we can combine thinking in bets with perspective taking, where we look at the outcome of someone else and imagine if that had happened to us. By doing this, we are more likely to find things that they did well and we can learn from. Likewise, when an outcome happens to us, let’s examine the result as if it happened to someone else. This way, we will be more likely to find things that we could have improved on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Perspective taking gets us closer to the truth because that truth generally lies in the middle of the way we field outcomes for ourselves and the way we field them for others.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The hard way&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking in bets is incredibly difficult, especially at the beginning. It’s important to remember that it is not about being perfect, as it may not make sense at times and you may even catch yourself falling into the biases we discussed. However, being able to push through these difficulties will mean that eventually it does become a habit of mind. Then, you will be able to compound on your experiences over time (even 1% a day will make a huge difference in the long run).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The first step is identifying the habit of mind that we want to reshape and how to reshape it. That first step is hard and takes time and effort and a lot of missteps along the way. So the second step is recognizing that it is easier to make these changes if we weren't alone in the process. Recruiting help is key to creating faster and more robust change, strengthening and training our new truth-seeking routines. (this leads into Chapter 4, The Buddy System)&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>

        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://koan-trading.com//blog/education/2020/04/29/thinking-in-bets-chapter-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://koan-trading.com//blog/education/2020/04/29/thinking-in-bets-chapter-3/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Principles - Ray Dalio (Part 2)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/education/ray_dalio_principles.jpg" alt="Principles by Ray Dalio (Pic: veronicastenberg.com)" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part 2 covers Ray’s fundamental life principles. It discusses ideas about our acceptance and understanding of reality, the five types of choices we have to make, higher level thinking and system (planning) design, as well as a 5-step process to achieving your goals. Part 2 is quite lengthy, so we will only go over the major ideas. I highly recommend you to read the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life Lessons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a brief introduction to his life and how he came upon his love for the markets (as well as his goal to beat the market), Ray goes on to talk about what the pursuit of this goal had taught him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the markets, you can do a huge amount of work and still be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bad opinions can be very costly, especially in the market. This is why you need to be cautious, no matter how hard you work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The consensus is often wrong, so you need to be an independent thinking. To make any money, you have to be right when they’re wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve these goals, it’s important to work for yourself, to come up with independent opinions, to stress-test them, to be wary about being confident, and to reflect on the consequences of your decisions and constantly improve. This is the bare-bones system for getting what you want in life, which we will go into more detail further on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray also goes on to discuss his academic life, as well as his experience in starting Bridgewater. He lists a few of the mistakes that he made, and the lessons he’s learned from them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Failure is largely due to not accepting and successfully dealing with the realities of life. Achieving success is simply a matter of accepting and successfully dealing with all your realities.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is nothing to fear from truth. While some truths may be scary, knowing them allows us to deal with them better. Being truthful allows us to fully explore our thoughts and expose ourselves to the essential feedback that is required for learning.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s important for the people you deal with to have integrity (say what they really believe) and to listen to what others say in reply in order to find out what is true.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Everyone makes mistakes and has weaknesses, and that what differentiates people is there approach to handling these mistakes. If you could figure out the root of the mistakes, you could learn to be more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nobody is born great (everyone has weaknesses), and everyone makes lots of mistakes on the way to greatness. The people who make the most of the process of encountering reality (especially the painful obstacles) are able to learn the most and achieve their goals faster than the ones who don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Most Fundamental Principle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Success is achieved by people who deeply understand reality and know how to use it to get what they want... idealists who are not well-grounded in reality create problems, not progress.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most fundamental principle: Truth, or an accurate understanding of reality, is the essential foundation for producing good outcomes. For example, what does “good” and “bad” mean? You may find that for the majority of people, these words simply reflect their own (or their group’s) preferences. These paradigms are held to provide structure and paint a picture of the world for us in a way in which we can live. However, depending on whichever group a person belongs to, there are so many different takes on what is “good” and what is “bad”. Yet, all of these takes are subject to the same laws of nature:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;...we all get rewarded and punished according to whether we operate in harmony or in conflict with nature's laws, and that all societies will succeed or fail in the degree that they operate consistently with these laws.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a pack of hyenas taking down a wildebeest is not inherently “bad” (although that is what your first reaction may be). Instead, it is a complex combination of actions derived from an incredibly efficient system (nature) with not only first-order but second- and third-order consequences as well. This interaction, while may seem “bad”, is fueling the interests of the greater system (i.e. the natural process of improvement/evolution). Interfering with this dynamic would only create a worse overall outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By understanding this, we can see that it is the sequence of seeking new goals, working and learning in the process of pursuing these goals, obtaining these goals, and then repeating this process over and over again is what fulfills the majority of people and progresses society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Most Important Choices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five big types of choices that you must continually make in your lives. These choices drastically affect the quality of your life and the rate at which you move toward your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, how you face (or run away from) pain will determine your progress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bad: Allow pain to stand in the way of their progress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good: Understand how to manage pain to produce progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, how you view reality will affect the way you anticipate consequences and deal with decision-making:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bad: Avoid facing “harsh realities”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good: Face “harsh realities”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, what you worry about affects the way you are able to identify and deal with your weaknesses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bad: Worry about appearing good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good: Worry about achieving the goal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth, how you react to the decisions with different orders of consequence, where short-term consequences (short-term pain) often have inverse desirability with long-term consequences (long-term gain):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bad: Make their decisions on the basis of first-order consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good: Make their decisions on the basis of first-, second-, and third-order consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five, how you handle bad outcomes affects your ability to reflect and progress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bad: Don’t hold themselves accountable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good: Hold themselves accountable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your Two Yous and Your Machine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly successful people are capable of “higher level thinking”. This is where they are able to step back and design a “machine” consisting of the all the rights people doing the right things to achieve their goals. An important concept here is the ability to assess, iterate, and improve on their machine and how it works (think: open feedback loop) by comparing the outcomes that the machine is producing with their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of yourself as being two people. One is a designer of the plan that you will execute to achieve your goals. The other is the person actually executing this plan. Success will require the designer you to be objective about the participant you. For example, as the designer of the plan, why would you assign the participant you things that they are not capable or as skilled at doing? Wouldn’t you allocate your resources differently, and maybe look for outside talent to help fill in the weaknesses of the participant you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The biggest mistake most people make is to not see themselves and others objectively.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5-Step Process To Getting What You Want Out Of Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the five things you have to do to achieve your goals in life. Remember, this is an iterative process that will undoubtedly cause lots of pain along the way. You will either react badly to the pain or react like a master problem solver, that is your choice. Finally, remember that weaknesses don’t matter if you can find solutions (surround yourself with people who cover the areas you lack), but you need to first be able to analyze and identify these weaknesses objectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have clear goals. You can have virtually anything you want, but you can’t have everything you want. So you have to reject having some things you want in order to get other things you want more.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Identify and don’t tolerate the problems that stand in your way of achieving your goals. Come up with a plan or a design to achieve these and then execute this plan. Modify this design as needed, as most problems are simply potential improvements that could be made. In order to be successful, you have to be able to perceive these problems and fix them (identify and don’t tolerate).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Accurately diagnose these problems. You must stay calm, logical, and rational in order to come up with a proper solution. It is imperative that you get at the root causes, as this is the only way to get rid of your problems.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Design plans that explicitly lay out tasks that will get you around your problems and on to your goals. Visualize the goal or problem standing in your way, and then visualize practical solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Implement these plans - i.e., do these tasks. Great planners who don’t carry out their plans go nowhere. You need to “push through” to accomplish your goals.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some general points about the process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Approach these as distinct steps rather than blur them together. Doing each step thoroughly will provide information that will help you do the other steps well, since the process is iterative.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Each of the five steps requires different talents and disciplines. You can always acquire any of the talents or disciplines you require (as long as you recognize your weaknesses and design around them).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s imperative that you approach the process in a rational manner as opposed to emotionally. To do this, you need to figure out what techniques work best for you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treat your life like a game or a martial art. Try to figure out how to get around your challenges and to get to your goals. As you get better, you will progress to higher and higher levels of the game that subsequently require higher and higher levels of skill. This will challenge you in ways that will be uncomfortable and difficult. But, by working through the discomfort you will greatly improve your chances of achieving what you set out to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://koan-trading.com//blog/education/2020/04/28/principles-ray-dalio-pt2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://koan-trading.com//blog/education/2020/04/28/principles-ray-dalio-pt2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekly Market Analysis (April 27th, 2020)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/market-analysis/042720-XBTUSD.png" alt="4H Chart for XBTUSD (Bitmex)" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another week of green! Bulls have really stepped on the gas pedal this week, breaking through significant HTF resistance on relatively high volume. However, is this a bull trap or will we see a big green dildo soon? Coronavirus is still causing mass shutdowns and quarantine as the infected numbers and death tolls keep rising. Yet, stock markets are still holding strong thanks to the endless printing of cash that is the Fed (and now the BOJ too brrrrrrrrrr). Bitcoin’s correlation to equities have seemed to simmer a bit, but are still an interesting point of interest moving forward. After bulls plowed through North Korea FUD (/s), posts about “missing the generational buy” began popping up on Crypto Twitter (accompanied with enough fractal charts to create medically induced FOMO in even the strongest of bears). Let’s take a look at the charts. Next week will be the monthly market recap, where we will take a look at the weekly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Context&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Price is really at a decision point, so it is difficult to provide any useful actionable information besides “if reject = short, if green dildo, long”. So, to keep it short, we are still making higher highs and higher lows. As discussed last week, a break of the 7.3k-7.4k area would most likely mean an 8k test is imminent. It’s safe to say that this area is a key area of interest and line in the sand. So, it wouldn’t be surprising to see this major level wick through multiple times to stop out as many traders as possible before any further movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From information taken from Deribit Insights (@DeribitInsights), it seems that options traders are becoming more bearish on Bitcoin. Large amounts of far-out OTM calls were sold yesterday, causing a sharp decline in the price of the calls. Tony (@PelionCap), one of the contributors for Deribit Insights, also noted that 6-7k May puts were being consistently bought (and 8-10k calls being sold relatively heavily).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still in our ascending wedge we discussed last week, although we are nearing the point of intersection. Price broke through the HTF Point of Control at 7.3-7.4k on substantial volume. We then saw a nice rounded retest to confirm the support/resistance flip. Currently, price is sitting below another HTF resistance (which is also a Low Volume Node, meaning that there is higher probability of it getting filled out with activity). However, volume is continuing to decrease, suggesting either a tightening of volatility (= big move soon) or buyer exhaustion (reversal soon). Weekly RSI is neutral, but daily RSI is slowly starting to approach over-bought territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the upside, we have the Golden Pocket Fibonacci level (61.8% - 65%) setting between 7863 and 8086. Many traders will be looking to enter shorts at this level, so it is unclear if this may be front-run, or if price will blow through this level to stop all of these traders out before continuing to the downside (or continuation). Conservative stops could probably be placed past the 70.5% Fibonacci at 8468.5. A more aggressive position could have stops placed at 8200+, but run the risk of being stop-ran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have a bearish bias, it seems that I am in the majority. Therefore, there is definitely a serious possibility of either a very large green candle, or some really long wicks to stop everyone out. However, I do think that whatever reaction price has here will be a significant turning point in the market (as in it will set the tone for the coming months). To be honest, Bitcoin’s correlation with equities has declined but I still think equities will be where to look for the long-term direction of Bitcoin. It would be a good idea to hedge some exposure to both spot and crypto at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bullish, neutral, and bearish cases remain the same as last week. Click on the post below to go to last week’s post!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://koan-trading.com//blog/market-analysis/2020/04/27/weekly-market-analysis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://koan-trading.com//blog/market-analysis/2020/04/27/weekly-market-analysis/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekly Debrief (April 26th, 2020)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/trader-progress/march-performance-review.jpeg" alt="Weekly Debrief - Net Positive but Terrible Risk Management" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main focus of this week was to test out a high volume node scalp strategy. Overall, the testing went fantastic and I’m slowly dialing in the variables I need to trade this on a regular basis. Trading on the other hand, didn’t go as well. While I am net positive for the week, I had an abysmal win-rate. I basically did everything you shouldn’t do this week, like revenge trade, over-leverage, no system, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit: Ended up taking a successful flip of an absorption level for a clean 4R! Amazing way to end what was a terrible week. This one was a real analyzed setup. Will go over it in a post next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trades Taken: 13&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winners: 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losers: 9&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winrate: 30.77%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PnL: 4.48%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason for the poor performance is mainly psychological and lack of patience. I struggled very hard this week with simply waiting for opportunities. Instead, I entered the market at the completely wrong times using position sizes that are way too large. A big portion of the losses were due to me learning and testing the high volume node strategy, but losses should not cause me to go on tilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my market analysis has only continued to improve. I am able to effectively identify when my setups are occurring and their optimal entry conditions. This gives me great optimism because I am lacking greatly in confidence of my own skills. This lack of confidence is one of the main reasons that I am unable to execute my analysis and often go on psychological tilt. I think time will be the key here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I continued to learn about order flow, particularly the footprint tool. I learned multiple different setups as well as concepts that I am trying to apply to my trading. I’ve also picked up the discounted course from MacroHedged (Options), and so far it’s going very well. While I am not an options trader, I think that learning about it can only aid me in my journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For books, I continued reading Thinking In Bets, Markets In Profile, Mind Over Markets, and Principles. But, I also picked up Anna Couling’s Complete Guide To Volume Profile. To be honest, I haven’t read as much as I should have this week, so I need to improve on that next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next Steps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I would like to continue to test and develop this high volume node strategy as I work my way through the MacroHedged options course. I also want to continue reading books primarily on volume profile, market profile, order flow, and general psychology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week’s goals include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MacroHedged Options Course&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More exercise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trust development for my own trading + psychological barriers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>

        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://koan-trading.com//blog/trader-progress/2020/04/26/weekly-debrief/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://koan-trading.com//blog/trader-progress/2020/04/26/weekly-debrief/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trade Review - XBTUSD (April 25th, 2020)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/Screen Shot 4-24-2020 at 11.52 PM.png" alt="Trade Review (XBTUSD: Short) - Double Distribution" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin formed a clean double distribution TPO setup after it’s rally from 6.8k to 7.5k. Price wicked into the double print TPO low twice, eventually consolidated at the double print before ultimately breaking down (this consolidation was the key to this trade, as it meant that buyers were no longer aggressively responding to the “discount” in prices).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Screen Shot 4-24-2020 at 11.46 PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Double Distribution Setup&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Execution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market entry for this needs to be aggressive, as the movements are often quick and violent (and only valid on the break of structure). The typical target for this type of trade is the upper portion of the second distribution. However, there was the presence of a high volume node in the footprint chart, which made a good exit target and a perfect place to flip directional bias into a long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stops would be difficult to place for this as it is such a low-time frame scalp. Going for a safe stop will dramatically reduce your RR so a extremely tight stop is probably optimal (or even manual close for those with more experience).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to catch the breakdown, but failed to set a take profit at the high volume node. I ended up closing in mediocre profit but missed the bulk of the profit of the move as well as the bias flip. This was pretty upsetting because I had previously marked the high volume node with long entries only to cancel them mere hours before this trade occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Screen Shot 4-24-2020 at 10.24 PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Footprint High Volume Node&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, my analysis of the markets has tremendously improved, but my execution and ability to use this analysis is god-awful. This is most likely due to a lack of experience and patience. It seems I am not patient enough to allow my analysis to come to fruition, as this has happened multiple times over the past few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was still a win, albeit 1/5th of the optimal project. This was basically the only win I had this week that had sound analysis behind it. I got pretty rekt this week getting lost into the noise, trying out new strategies, not sticking to my system, and just trading on full tilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall Score:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setup: Above Average - 6/10 (great initial analysis of the double distribution setup, good improvement for spotting the high volume node a day before, but poor performance for not being able to add all these variables together when it mattered)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Execution: Below Average - 3/10 (the double distribution entry was fine, but this trade basically lay itself out for me and I still wasn’t able to capitalize on it. Talk about dropping the ball!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trade Management: Below Average - 4/10 (failure to assimilate all of this different information into )&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://koan-trading.com//blog/trader-progress/2020/04/25/trade-review-xbtusd/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://koan-trading.com//blog/trader-progress/2020/04/25/trade-review-xbtusd/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thinking In Bets (Annie Duke) - Chapter 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/education/thinking-in-bets.jpeg" alt="Annie Duke - Thinking In Bets (Aidan Hornsby - Medium)" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time, we covered Chapter 1 of “Thinking In Bets” by Annie Duke. We talked about the idea of separating instances of luck vs. skill, as well as being less outcome dependent when we frame the way we look at our decisions. Additionally, we discussed about being comfortable with this idea of uncertainty, where we strive to make the most optimal decisions in a game of limited information. Chapter 2 discusses re-framing our decisions into “bets”, the inherent problems with our beliefs and biases, as well as redefining what it means to be confident in our decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Chapter 2: Wanna Bet?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Playing poker for a living has the allure of giving you the freedom to make your own schedule but, once it boils down to your per-hour net advantage, you are tethered to putting in the hours. You're &quot;free&quot; to play or not to play whenever you want, but you can feel compelled to punch a clock.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quote really struck a chord with me because of it’s application to trading. We often trade because we want the flashy models and bottles on yacht lifestyle that we see from “successful” traders trying to sell us $3000 courses that they ripped straight from somewhere or someone. But, when it comes down to it, you need to put in the hours. Keep in mind this does not mean you need to be “in the market” all this time, just like a poker player doesn’t need to play every single hand. But being “at the table” and present even when nothing is going on is a crucial aspect of this game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapter 2 talks all about the decisions that we make. Every decision that we make (and others make) is in one form or another, a type of bet. A bet that this decision will add value to our life (whether short-term, long-term, it doesn’t matter). By treating our decisions as bets, we need to recognize that we are effectively deciding on alternative futures, each with benefits and risks. Additionally, these futures have certain unknowns and “what-ifs” that we must be okay with accepting. The goal of this book is to understand the thought processes behind our decisions and our psychology so that we can ultimately make better decisions and anticipate when our irrationality may be leading us astray from optimality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s change our traditional view of betting (wagering against someone else on a chance of a favorable outcome of some event) to a more broad one: a choice made by thinking about what will probably happen, and to risk losing something when you try to do or achieve something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;No matter how far we get from the familiarity of betting at a poker table or in a casino, our decisions are always bets. We routinely decide among alternatives, put resources at risk, assess the likelihood of different outcomes, and consider what it is that we value. Every decision commits us to some course of action that, by definition, eliminates acting on other alternatives. Not placing a bet on something is, itself, a bet.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more examples of decisions re-framed as bets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Going to the movies - we are choosing to not do all the other things with our time that we might do during those hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parenting choices - we are betting that our choice will achieve the future we want for our child more than any other choice we may make&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Job and relocation decisions, sales negotiations and contracts, buying a house, ordering the chicken instead of the steak. These are all bets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we don’t think of decisions as bets is because we attach the zero-sum nature of betting to our concept of a bet (ie. betting against somebody else where one person wins and one person loses). However, in most of our decisions we are betting against all of the future versions of ourselves that we are not choosing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Have you ever had a moment of regret after a decision where you felt, &quot;I knew I should have made the other choice!&quot;? That's an alternative version of you saying, &quot;See, I told you so!&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, how can we make sure we are choosing the best alternative? Well, we can’t. There are things that are out of our control and we live in a world with imperfect and hidden information. The best that we can do is to make the best guess given the information at hand, and learn to be comfortable with this uncertainty. However, all is not lost! The good news is that through experience, we can become more effective navigators of our beliefs in situations with imperfect information. Additionally, there is also skill in the ability to identify when our thinking patterns are leading us down the wrong alleyway, and we can use this skill to develop strategies to work with or around our thinking patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how you think you form beliefs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You hear something&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You think about its validity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You form your beliefs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in reality, the process is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You hear something&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You believe it to be true&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You vet it later if you have time to determine its validity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about this, you can take a look at the idea of System 1 and System 2 from Dan Kahneman’s Thinking, Fast and Slow (and others, this is just the most easily digestible one), because this is exactly how your mind works in order to minimize unnecessary workload or strain on its System 2. We discussed this briefly in the Chapter 1 Summary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good example of the bias in our beliefs can be seen in a 1954 paper titled “They Saw a Game”, and a 2012 Stanford Law Review called “They Saw a Protest”. Essentially, if you show the same thing to different groups (each with their own set of beliefs), each group will exhibit biases that conform to their set of beliefs. For example if you show a Princeton student a Princeton football game, he/she is more likely to see instances where the other team committed fouls or penalties. Likewise, if you show a student from the opposing school the same film, he/she will actually be more inclined to see more fouls or penalities committed by the Princeton team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Once a belief is lodged, it becomes difficult to dislodge... leading us to notice and seek out evidence confirming our belief, rarely challenge the validity of confirming evidence, and ignore or work hard to actively discredit information contradicting the belief...[this] is called motivated reasoning.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans are stubborn as hell. We hear what we want to hear and get upset if other people disagree with our beliefs, even when confronted with facts or reasoning. This is because we think of our beliefs as black and white (100% right or 100% wrong). Therefore, we only have two options: to either create a massive shift in our opinion from right to wrong, or to ignore or discredit any new information. Obviously, it feels bad to be wrong so most people choose Option 2. Additionally, being intelligent can actually make this bias worse. This is because the smarter you are, the better you are at creating a narrative that justifies and supports your beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;We are wired to protect our beliefs even when our goal is to truthseek.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do we fix this? We can train ourselves to view the world through the phrase: “Wanna bet?”. This phrase forces us to confront Step 3 of our belief process (vetting it later if you have time to determine its validity). Being asked if we are willing to bet money on it makes us much more likely to examine the information in an unbiased and objective manner. The more honest we are with our perspective, the more accurate our beliefs become. Additionally, we can try to change the way we think about “right” or “wrong” by incorporating uncertainty into our beliefs. For example, instead of saying “Citizen Kane won the Oscar for best picture”, we can say something like: “I think Citizen Kane won the Oscar for best picture, but I’m only a six (60% sure) on that.” By stating our level of certainty, we force ourselves to express how sure we are of our beliefs and brings the probabilistic nature of those beliefs to light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The person who wins bets over the long run is the one with the more accurate beliefs.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incorporating uncertainty into the way we think about our beliefs can help us in a multitude of areas. Expressing our level of confidence in our beliefs allows us to shift our approach to our view of the world. By acknowledging uncertainty, we take the first step in being able to measure and narrow it down. Working towards belief calibration also allows us to become less judgmental on ourselves, as we are no longer tied to a black and white, 100% or 0% narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://koan-trading.com//blog/education/2020/04/24/thinking-in-bets-chapter-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://koan-trading.com//blog/education/2020/04/24/thinking-in-bets-chapter-2/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stepping Away From Support and Resistance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/market-analysis/042320-XBTUSD.png" alt="How I Draw My Charts Using Volume Profile (XBTUSD) - TradingView" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Buy support, sell resistance. -basically every trader ever&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of support and resistance is one of the oldest facets of trading, and for good reason. It can be drawn in such a way that is clear to even a complete beginner, and I believe that it’s perceived simplicity is what makes it such a powerful and prevalent idea. However, is it really that easy? What really is support and resistance? If we’re going to be honest, aren’t we just drawing lines on a chart? And how come it works sometimes and doesn’t work other times? What is price really doing, “under the hood”, as we might say? Today, I want to go over the driving mechanics behind support and resistance, as well as potentially challenge and analyze a few of my own beliefs and ideas (and perhaps even some of yours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: This post serves as a “brain-dump” for a lot of the concepts that I have been learning about. It serves as a journal of sorts for me, a place to collect my thoughts and expand upon them. Only by writing my ideas down as if I am explaining them to someone will I be able to effectively gauge how much I know/don’t know, as well as identify areas where I am lacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Support and Resistance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support and resistance, from how we see it in action, are often simple lines drawn at key areas where the market seemed to have reversed direction. However, anyone who has ever traded can tell you that it is definitely not that simple. Levels get blown through all the time, and price will even extend past or never reach it on a regular basis. This is because the support and resistances that we draw are nothing more than lines on a chart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I dislike drawing lines as support and resistance is the simplicity of it. Yes, it makes your chart look clean and you can get some clout on Crypto Twitter. But, if you can see it, so can everyone else. And that makes you an easy target. Now, don’t get me wrong, I’m not saying that you should never use lines for levels. The important thing to note here is to not be blinded by them that you fail to recognize external factors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, setting levels using lines may cause you to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get stopped out before price reverses in your predicted direction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Miss a move because price didn’t reach your entry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To minimize this occurrence, we need to understand how price moves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Do Prices Move?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prices move because there is an imbalance in the activity of buyers or sellers. Many people may say that prices go up if there are more buyers than sellers, but given the way that markets work (a seller for every buyer, and vice versa) that is not technically correct. Instead, prices move when there is an imbalance in the aggressiveness of market participants. If buyers are impatient, they will aggressively bid up price until they believe that it is above value, and vice versa. This idea of a “two-way” auction, where buyers and sellers will react accordingly to below or above value prices is the key concept of auction market theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, if prices move due to an imbalance in the aggressiveness of buyers and sellers, what makes price stop? The answer is liquidity. When there is an imbalance in market participant aggression, the market will move until it hits available liquidity. This liquidity will either get eaten up by the aggressive side (and price will continue), or it will prove too strong and price will fail to push through. This is why simply looking at a candlestick chart does not give us enough information about what is actually happening in the battle between buyers and sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if prices have nothing to do with support and resistance lines that we draw, how can we effectively look for entries and targets? This is where we can use things like market profile, volume profile, and order flow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Role of Volume Profile/Market Profile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, volume and market profile lets me see the market from a bird’s eye view. While the two measure different things (one is volume and the other is time), I use them similarly: to show me where buyers/sellers interacted the most. It allows me to spot potential areas of interest through high volume areas and low volume areas. For those of you not familiar with volume or market profile, I highly recommend checking out some online resources (the gentlemen over at Blockroots have an amazing course, and I’ve heard great things about BTCMarketProfile as well as some of the courses from Axia Futures. Alternatively, you can read a few books that I’ve listed at the bottom of this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, I look at two things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Point of Control - I mark these with a green box to indicate to me key areas where market participation was the highest. These often act as support and resistance to price. If you think about the mechanics behind this, this means that at these prices, there was a lot of volume transacted (meaning that at one point, it was a fair value area between buyers/sellers). Hence, it goes to reason that it will be an important area of interest in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Low Volume Areas - I mark these with a blue box to indicate key areas where market participation was low. These are areas where price was below or above value, and buyers or sellers aggressively reacted and immediately took price away from this area (hence the low volume). You may notice that while these act as support and resistance, they will sometimes also be filled out and turned into high volume areas as price comes back and the reactions of the market participants change.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this gives us a good idea of the overall market context, it isn’t accurate enough. Trying to find entries with boxes often gives you a terrible risk:reward unless you’re trading on the higher-time frames. This is where order flow comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Role of Order Flow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If volume/market profile is a bird’s eye view, then order flow is the sniper. It allows you to look into exactly what buyers/sellers transacted at every price point in every candle. Again, I highly recommend checking out something like Blockroots, or some online resources. Currently, EXOCharts is in my opinion the best order flow platform for crypto, with Sierra Charts also being incredibly good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For order flow, I follow a similar process except on a much lower time frame. I’ve found that it is incredibly good at giving you high R:R, low time frame scalps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;High Volume Nodes - I look for price to wick into these areas of high volume. Great for finding pockets of liquidity that almost attracts price like a magnet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Delta - Delta is the difference in executed orders between the buy and sell side, aggregated for each candle. It shows you the intentions behind the market participants, as lots of aggressive buying will show heavy positive delta (and vice versa for heavy selling). In an uptrend for example, we want to see sustained positive delta. If we begin to see a shift in delta participation from positive to negative, it could tell us buyers are beginning to lose steam and exhaust themselves (aka no more buyers).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Absorption - absorption is important to confirm direction. For any moves, we want to ideally see buyers/sellers absorbing in the direction of the move. For example, on a trend upwards, we want to see buyers absorb (or “reload”) at higher and higher prices, indicating that there are still buyers in the market. If we see heavy selling into clear signs of absorption, it is a sign that buyers are willing to buy at these higher prices, and continuation is probable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t cover a few ideas such as cumulative volume delta, buy/sell imbalances and divergences, so maybe I will save those for a later post. Basically, we want to ask ourselves “where is price trying to go”, and “is it doing a good job of getting there?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Suggested Reading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anne Couling - A Complete Guide to Volume Profile&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;James F. Dalton - Mind Over Markets and Markets In Profile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you made it this far, thanks very much for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://koan-trading.com//blog/market-analysis/2020/04/23/stepping-away-from-support-and-resistance/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://koan-trading.com//blog/market-analysis/2020/04/23/stepping-away-from-support-and-resistance/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Principles - Ray Dalio (Part 1)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/education/ray_dalio_principles.jpg" alt="Principles by Ray Dalio (Pic: veronicastenberg.com)" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Principles are concepts that can be applied over and over again in similar circumstances as distinct from narrow answers to specific questions... Principles are ways of successfully dealing with the laws of nature or the laws of life. Those who understand more of them and understand them well know how to interact with the world more effectively than those who know fewer of the mor know them less well.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray Dalio’s “Principles” dives into the mind of one of the most successful hedge fund managers of all time. In Part 1, he discusses the idea of purpose and the importance of having fundamental life principles. He encourages the reader to explore and discover his/her own set of principles, and hopes that this process will allow the reader to come to his/her own encounters with reality and their reflections on these encounters (rather than blindly accepting someone else’s principles).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1: The Importance of principles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part of Principles begins with a look into a few questions essential to understanding each other’s principles (and by extension to understand each other).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are principles?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Values that you consider important (literally what you “value”). Principles connect your values to your actions, and help you deal with the laws of reality. In hard times or times of tough choices, you turn to your principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are principles important?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;All successful people operate by principles that help them be successful.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Principles create a sense of order, and without them you would be forced to be reactionary to the happenings around you. Operating without principles is bad for individuals and worse for groups (it leads to a lack of understanding of their own values and how to behave in order to be consistent with those values).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do principles come from?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be difficult to come up with your own principles, but adopting pre-packaged principles without much self-thought exposes you to an inconsistency risk with your own true values. Your principles need to be a reflection of the true values that you believe in (incompatible principles lead to conflict).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have principles that you live your life by? What are they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Your principles will determine your standards of behavior... People who have shared values and principles get along. People who don't will suffer throug constant misunderstandings and conflicts with one another.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you value most deeply?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How well do you think they will work, and why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Those principles that are most valuable come from our own experiences and our reflections on those experiences. Every time we face hard choices, we refine our principles by asking ourselves difficult questions.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be most effective, principles must be consistent with your values, and this requires you to ask the question: Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be successful, you must make correct but tough choices; to be a great leader, you must remember that you will have to make these choices by understanding and caring for your people, not by following them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He goes on to remind the reader that when considering each principle, please ask yourself: “Is it true?” It’s important to never blindly adopt other people’s principles, but rather to carefully consider and discuss each one. Everyone ultimately operates on their own set of principles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://koan-trading.com//blog/education/2020/04/21/principles-ray-dalio-pt1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://koan-trading.com//blog/education/2020/04/21/principles-ray-dalio-pt1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekly Market Analysis (April 20th, 2020)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/images/market-analysis/042020-XBTUSD.png" alt="4H Chart for XBTUSD (Bitmex)" class="webfeedsFeaturedVisual"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week ended as the 5th consecutive green week on the weekly chart. Price has been steadily increasing ever since the massive sell-off in mid-March. Halvening posts are rampant across Twitter as gigabulls cry for the downfall of the traditional monetary system in favor of decentralized cryptocurrency (with permabears calling for sub 2k prices). Coronavirus fears are still at an all-time high as countries struggle to contain it and enforce social distancing and quarantine procedures. However, I’m not an economist so I have really no idea what I’m talking about from a fundamental analysis standpoint. Let’s take a look at the 4H Bitcoin chart, as see if there are any clues as to its next directional move. Current price action for the past few weeks have been extremely choppy, as the huge volatility swings of the post-March crash have subsided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green Box = High Volume Node&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue Box = Low Volume Node&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The primary goal of this is not to provide in-depth actionable market information or analysis. It’s merely an exercise for me to do every week to stay up-to-date with the market + train myself to quickly analyze and view the big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Context&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, Bitcoin has been consistently making higher highs and higher lows, stair-stepping it’s way past both high and low volume nodes. For bulls, a v-bottom reversal looks like it’s in the books, as price is slowly grinding up towards resistance (likely 7.7-8k area). However, it’s worth it to note that this price increase has been on decreasing volume, a combination that is often interpreted as bearish (we want to see volume confirm the trend). It can also be argued that after a capitulation-style dump like the one we saw in March, lower volume is natural (see 2018/19 bottom). After the rejection from the 7.4k area, we saw price trade relatively sideways until it ultimately wicked into 6.5k before buyers grabbed the initiative and pushed price all the way to the 7.3k Point of Control. Today, we did see a rejection from this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Bitcoin’s correlation with the equities market has dropped a bit, the upcoming weeks will be incredibly vital. If the equities market can complete a v-bottom reversal, then Bitcoin will likely follow. However, if the current rally turns out to be nothing more than a relief rally, Bitcoin will most likely follow in the drop. I don’t know enough about economics or fundamentals to give accurate analysis on this, but all eyes are on the Federal Reserve and their money-printing machine. The recent aid given to small businesses has already run out of money, but a new 2k/month stimulus is in the works of being discussed. Can the Fed keep propping up the economy? The similarities of this crash to previous ones are shockingly similar (particularly the Great Depression). Large crash followed by heavy ~50 retrace, followed by further downside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a technical standpoint, we are developing a rising wedge which is seen as a bearish pattern. Additionally we tested the 7.3k point of control before before rejected on relatively high volume (2x the 20 day average). This structure could be argued as the first lower high of the structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, 6.3k still has a naked Point of Control that has yet to be touched (which coincides nicely with a technical break target of this rising wedge). On-balance volume seems to have topped out as well, showing higher buyer participation but with price decreasing. The relative strength index shows no real conviction in either direction. Price is hovering at the 50% Fibonacci retracement level from the 10k top, but seemed to be unable to reclaim this level. Open Interest has been steadily decreasing on moves up (generally bearish), but have recently begun to increase as price increases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current price action from the past week closely resembles price action from the end of March and beginning of April. However, as is the nature of fractals, market structure also resembles the entire structure from the recent 10k trend in Jan/Feb/early March, where price ultimately failed to make higher highs and began to crash (leading to the March 12/13 crash).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bullish Case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bulls would want to see 7.4k get reclaimed, which all but guarantees a 7.7-8k retest. If price is able to reclaim this level, then it could be fair to say that the v-bottom reversal is complete, and next targets would be around 10k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is clear that institutions are investing into Bitcoin, but the extent to which they are doing so is not quite clear at this point. The infamous Stock-2-Flow model also predicts a rapid increase in the price of Bitcoin after the halvening. Overall, it’s easy to see the bullish reasons for Bitcoin, and I think that having a reasonable level of exposure here would be a smart idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If 6.9k breaks, then price would need to find support at 6.4k to build a base for further extension. Otherwise, it can be safe to say that the bullish case is invalidated and we can move to the neutral case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best long-term strategy: Buy-hold&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best trading strategy: Dips are for buying&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutral Case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is potential for a Wyckoff Accumulation schematic to occur here, but it is difficult to determine the presence of the upwards thrust until we see downwards price action. A completion of this schematic would see price range between ~7.5k and 3k. If this were to come true, then the next few months would see incredibly choppy price action as whales are able to easily manipulate and control the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A range like this would most likely last well into the second quarter of 2021, with multiple retests of both the 3.5-4k area as well as the 7-7.4k area (assuming that the upwards thrust has already been seen). This will give investors ample time to accumulate at relatively cheap prices, and given the efficiency of the Bitcoin mining hardware (allegedly), won’t be too cheap that miners will be forced to liquidate their holdings and cause a downward spiral of selling pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If price were to break the 4k area, it would most likely test the 2018/19 bottom. If that were to fail to hold, then we can say that the neutral case is invalidated and move towards the bearish case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best long-term strategy: Dollar-Cost Average&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best trading strategy: Swing trade the range extremes and scalp the tight mini-ranges using order flow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bearish Case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bears would want to see price ultimately drop below 3k and head towards the previous bull run’s ATH at around 1.2k. Price may ultimate end up ranging between there and 3k for an extended accumulation phase. If this were to happen, it would cause massive pressure to less efficient miners, possibly  resulting in miner capitulation. We would see the network hash rate drop drastically as miners are forced to close businesses, and a full network “cleansing” would take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the fact that each successive bullrun takes exponentially longer to complete (regardless of halvening time), this could be a real potential outcome. From a logical perspective, it makes sense. Bitcoin has become an established asset with a relatively mid-size market cap. In order to propel it to the 100k+ predictions, a long and extended accumulation phase is almost necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the 1k area were to fail to hold, then there is serious argument not only for the invalidation of the bearish case, but for Bitcoin as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best long-term strategy: Hail mary limit orders in increments of $100, starting from ~3k all the way down to sub-1k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best trading strategy: Swing short&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://koan-trading.com//blog/market-analysis/2020/04/20/weekly-market-analysis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://koan-trading.com//blog/market-analysis/2020/04/20/weekly-market-analysis/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
 
